Guide to the Faculty Senate Minutes 1971-2014
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Faculty Senate Minutes
1971-2014
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Archives 323
Washington State University. Faculty Senate.
7 Linear feet of shelf space 7 boxes
On April 12, 1971 WSU's Board of Regents approved the creation of a University Senate, which included undergraduate and graduate student representation, as well as faculty. On June 3, 1983, undergraduates were officially removed from the group, and the University Senate became the Faculty Senate. The collection solely of the minutes from the meetings of the Washington State University Faculty Senate and its predecessor, the University Senate.
According to the Washington State University (WSU) Faculty Senate web page (as of August 2012), "The mission of the Faculty Senate is to exercise the legislative powers delegated to it, and to make recommendations to the president and appropriate administrative officials of the University and through the President to the Board of Regents on matters affecting the general welfare of Washington State University and its educational, research, and service activities."
On April 12, 1971 WSU's Board of Regents approved the creation of a University Senate, which included undergraduate and graduate student representation, as well as faculty. The Senate originally arose out of student/faculty conflicts in the turbulent 1960s/1970s, and was intended as a place where faculty and student could cooperatively engage on legislative matters. On June 3, 1983, undergraduates were officially removed from the group, and the University Senate became the Faculty Senate.
The collection consists solely of the minutes from the meetings of the Washington State University Faculty Senate and its predecessor, the University Senate.
The collection was received in a single chronological series, and that arrangement was retained. The 1971-2000 years were received as bound volumes; subsequent years are individually foldered.
The Faculty Senate maintains, on their own website, pdf copies of the Faculty Senate Minutes, 1995-present.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Records from Washington State University’s Faculty Senate were received at the WSU Libraries’ Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections from Dorene Branson (Principal Assistant, Faculty Senate) on August 27, 2012 and retained as UA2012-04. Subsequent minutes have been received as accessions UA2012-08, UA2014-01, UA2014-14, UA2015-03, and UA2015-11 and incorporated into this collection; further accessions are expected but will be processed as a new collection.
Records of numerous other faculty committees are maintained in the WSU Libraries ' Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections, notably including Faculty Minutes, 1892-1911 (WSU 77), Faculty Council Records, 1972-1985 (Archives 208), and Faculty Executive Committee Records, 1934-1971 (Archives 27). Records of the Faculty Senate from 2015 forward are being received as individual accessions but are as of yet unprocessed.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington State University. Faculty Senate-- History -- Sources.; Washington State University. University Senate -- History -- Sources.; Washington State University. University Senate
Universities and colleges -- Faculty.
Colleges and Universities.; Washington (State)
- Bound Volumes
  - Sept. 1971 - May 1973 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - July 1973 - May 1975 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - Oct. 1975 - May 1977 (Box 1, Volume 3)
  - Oct. 1977 - May 1979 (Box 1, Volume 4)
  - Oct. 1979 - May 1980 (Box 1, Volume 5)
  - Oct. 1980 - May 1981 (Box 1, Volume 6)
  - Sept. 1981 - May 1982 (Box 1, Volume 7)
  - Oct. 1982 - May 1983 (Box 1, Volume 8)
  - Oct. 1983 - May 1984 (Box 1, Volume 9)
  - Sept. 1984 - May 1985 (Box 2, Volume 10)
  - Sept. 1985 - April 1986 (Box 2, Volume 11)
  - Sept. 1986 - April 1987 (Box 2, Volume 12)
  - Sept. 1987 - April 1988 (Box 2, Volume 13)
  - June 1988 - April 1989 (Box 2, Volume 14)
  - Sept. 1989 - May 1990 (Box 3, Volume 15)
  - Sept. 1990 - May 1991 (Box 3, Volume 16)
  - Sept. 1991 - Dec. 1991 (Box 3, Volume 17)
  - Jan. 1992 - April 1992 (Box 3, Volume 18)
  - Sept. 1992 - April 1993 (Box 3, Volume 19)
  - Sept. 1993 - April 1994 (Box 3, Volume 20)
  - Sept. 1994 - Dec. 1994 (Box 4, Volume 21)
  - Jan. 1995 - May 1995 (Box 4, Volume 22)
  - Sept. 1995 - May 1996 (Box 4, Volume 23)
  - Sept. 1996 - May 1997 (Box 4, Volume 24)
  - Sept. 1997 - April 1998 (Box 4, Volume 25)
  - Sept. 1998 - April 1999 (Box 4, Volume 26)
  - Sept. 1999 - April 2000 (Box 5, Volume 27)
- Folders
  - Sept. 2000 - Dec. 2000 (Box 5, Folders 1)
  - Feb. 2001 - March 2001 (Box 5, Folders 2)
  - Apr-01 (Box 5, Folders 3)
  - Sept. 2001 - Dec. 2001 (Box 5, Folders 4)
  - Jan. 2002 - Feb. 2002 (Box 5, Folders 5)
  - Feb. 2002 - April 2002 (Box 5, Folders 6)
  - Apr-02 (Box 5, Folders 7)
  - Sept. 2002 - Dec. 2002 (Box 5, Folders 8)
  - Jan. 2003 - Feb. 2003 (Box 5, Folders 9)
  - March 2003 - April 2003 (Box 5, Folders 10)
  - Apr-03 (Box 5, Folders 11)
  - Sept. 2003 - Oct. 2003 (Box 5, Folders 12)
  - Nov. 2003 - Dec. 2003 (Box 5, Folders 13)
  - Jan. 2004 - April 2004 (Box 5, Folders 14)
  - Apr-04 (Box 5, Folders 15)
  - Oct. 2004 - Dec. 2004 (Box 5, Folders 16)
  - Jan. 2005 - Feb. 2005 (Box 5, Folders 17)
  - March 2005- April 2005 (Box 5, Folders 18)
  - Sept. 2005 - Nov. 2005 (Box 6, Folders 19)
  - Jan. 2006 - Feb. 2006 (Box 6, Folders 20)
  - March 2006 - April 2006 (Box 6, Folders 21)
  - Oct. 2006 - Jan. 2007 (Box 6, Folders 22)
  - Feb. 2007 - March 2007 (Box 6, Folders 23)
  - Mar-07 (Box 6, Folders 24)
  - Apr-07 (Box 6, Folders 25)
  - Sept. 2007 - Nov. 2007 (Box 6, Folders 26)
  - Jan. 2008 - Feb. 2008 (Box 6, Folders 27)
  - March 2008 - April 2008 (Box 6, Folders 28)
  - Apr-08 (Box 6, Folders 29)
  - Oct. 2008 - Feb. 2009 (Box 6, Folders 30)
  - Feb. 2009 - April 2009 (Box 6, Folders 31)
  - Apr-09 (Box 6, Folders 32)
  - May-09 (Box 6, Folders 33)
  - Oct. 2009 - Jan. 2010 (Box 6, Folders 34)
  - Feb. 2010 (Box 6, Folders 35)
  - March 2010 - April 2010 (Box 6, Folders 36)
  - Apr-10 (Box 6, Folders 37)
  - Sept. 2010 - Oct. 2010 (Box 6, Folders 38)
  - Jan. 2011 (Box 6, Folders 39)
  - Feb. 2011 - March 2011 (Box 6, Folders 40)
  - March 2011 - April 2011 (Box 6, Folders 41)
  - Sept. 2011 (Box 6, Folders 42)
  - Oct. 2011 (Box 7, Folders 43)
  - Oct. 2011 - Jan. 2012 (Box 7, Folders 44)
  - Feb. 2012 (Box 7, Folders 45)
  - Feb. 2012 - March 2012 (Box 7, Folders 46)
  - Apr-12 (Box 7, Folders 47)
  - Sept. 2012 (Box 7, Folders 48)
  - Oct. 2012 (Box 7, Folders 49)
  - Nov. 2012 (Box 7, Folders 50)
  - Jan. 2013 (Box 7, Folders 51)
  - Feb. 2013 - March 2013 (Box 7, Folders 52)
  - Apr-13 (Box 7, Folders 53)
  - Sept. 2013 - Nov. 2013 (Box 7, Folders 54)
  - Nov. 2013 (Box 7, Folders 55)
  - Jan. 2014 (Box 7, Folders 56)
  - Feb. 2014 (Box 7, Folders 57-58)
  - Mar. 2014 (Box 7, Folders 59)
  - Apr. 2014 (Box 7, Folders 60)
  - Sept. 2014 (Box 7, Folders 61)
  - Oct. 2014 (Box 7, Folders 62-63)
  - Nov. 2014 (Box 7, Folders 64-65)